concerning TRT and administration uh
routes. Uh which do you prefer also the
injections and the creams like many
other of the guests on my channel at
least? That's a great question. Um you
know I I I would say in in my clinic
alone it's it's probably almost evenly
split. I I almost always when I when I
bring up uh and injections and creams
are by far my my two favorite options.
Um, if if I bring them up, I'm almost
always asking the patient, "Which one
struck you as something that you would
do." Uh, you know, if you're afraid of
needles, but you know, everybody says
you should do it that way. Maybe let's
not. Maybe let's start with creams. I
just need you to do it. Um, I want you
to be successful. It's like working out.
I mean, I could tell you that
weightlifting has all these amazing
facts and studies and and and truths,
but at the end of the day, if you like
yoga or swimming, I'd prefer you to do
something. So, um, but I personally, if
I, if I had a gun to my head, Stephen, I
would choose, uh, creams and topical
gels. They're unbelievably fantastic.
Um, and by the way, you you've been a
huge, uh, advocate for that, which I'm
I'm very appreciative of. Um, and and
many of my patients, they'll they'll
honestly they'll start with injections.
You know, I'll tell them, "Hey, in about
four or five months, the novelty will
wear off." And almost always are asking,
"Can you tell me a little bit more about
the creams and gels?" Again, Um, they
they've just been phenomenal in my in my
practice. I really do love just to hit
on that too. Um I I find a lot of my
patients seem to benefit and again this
is anecdotal um but I they seem to
benefit more from the topical creams in
terms of the the DHT uh or
dihydrotestosterone ratio to
testosterone. So um dihydrotestosterone
you know I in some weird way I almost
compare it to like progesterone but for
men it it it has a calming effect on the
central nervous system which is really
fascinating. um much like progesterone
does for for females. So, you know, I
actually occasionally will sometimes opt
for that if if I feel like a patient is,
you know, maybe a little bit more
anxious or something to that effect.
Mhm. I heard you mention um gels as
well. I I don't suppose you recommend 1%
gels to slather all over the shoulders?
No. Uh sorry, I should clarify.
Compounded creams and gels. uh not not
the uh not the androgels or testo gels,
not the not the crud I would say you
would get from a retail pharmacy. So um
I I particularly use a product at least
here in the United States. Um I know a
Trevous is is one of those products.
There's I think there's a slightly
better product. Um it's made by a
company called Medisca here. Uh but it's
an HRT gel. Um and and it's it's
fantastic. It has a little bit of a
liposomaal action to it. So, it's almost
kind of a combination close to a a
liposomaal cream and a HRT gel and
they're kind of mushing it together. Um,
and that has just been phenomenal for my
patients uh to a transcoral application.
[Music]